ABRAHAM FORSON

Software Engineer

Software engineer with over 3 years of experience writing and testing code, helping develop software system solutions, and updating companies' knowledge using the latest development tools. Well-skilled in software development life cycle, including requirement analysis, design, development, and production support. Key achievement: collaborated with a 5-member team to release a new system suite, saving the company monthly QA costs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jnr Software Engineer

April 2022 - May 2024

Aitech

- Assisted in developing a CRM software upgrade that improved customer service by 73%.
- Streamlined 17 existing applications for a more intuitive workflow; reduced interface complexity by 92%.
- Collaborated with a 5-member team to release a new system suite,
- Partnered with 11 supervisors to develop tools that reduced debugging time by 72%, saving engineers from repetitive tasks

Software Engineer Intern

February 2020 - October 2021

Upperlink (remote)

- Devised 14 web applications using React framework, increasing site traffic by 80% within the first month.
- Introduced an automated system for deploying software updates across 29 servers, reducing deployment time from 5 days to 24 hours
- Conceived a new system that tracked and analyzed 18TB of customerdata, increasing sales by 67%
- Developed scripts that automated tasks such as database backups and restores, and server provisioning, saving approximately 72 person-hours weekly.

CONTACT

· abforson01@gmail.com

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Debugging (Advanced)
- Coding (Experienced)
- Web programming
- Software design and testing
- · Web development

Industry Knowledge:

- Software Development
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

Tools and Software:

- Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, MERN stack (MongoDB, Express. js, React, and Node. Js)
- Programming Languages: Python (intermediate), Java (intermediate)
 C++(Advanced)
- JavaScript(Intermediate), MySQ(Intermediate),
- Development Tools: Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Git
- · CMS: word-press, wix, shopify

EDUCATION

BAze University

Bachelor of Science Computer Science majoring in software Engineering

Jan 2021 - Nov 2024